

Patrick A. Jain-Taylor

Boston, MA • (908) 340-9788 • patrick.andrew.taylor@gmail.com

Cloud Architect











Professional Cloud Architect with 7+ years of experience of Information Technology in the finance industry. Skilled in Amazon Web Services, Terraform, Python, and Networking. Strong focus on leadership, team building, and organizational advancement. How can I help?

Contact me

Experience

Eaton Vance Management, a Morgan Stanley company

Cloud Architect, Core Services • Apr. 2019 — Present

Subject matter expert on all things cloud, leading efforts in architecting, engineering, and operating in AWS.

- Designed Terraform account vending machine & multi-region landing zone for 40+ AWS accounts across the organization (CloudFormation, Config, EBS, EC2 Auto Scaling, ECR, KMS, IAM, PrivateLink, RDS, Route 53, Route 53 Resolver, Security Groups, Secrets Manager, S3, and VPC).
- Architected & deployed infrastructure for 70+ public websites (CloudFront, EventBridge, EC2 Auto Scaling, Elastic Load Balancing v2 [Application & Network], Lambda, SNS, Step Functions, RDS, WAF)

- Devised pull-based & push-based logging mechanisms for various AWS logs types to Splunk (Elastic Load Balancing v1, Kinesis Data Streams, Kinesis Firehose, Lambda, S3, SQS).
- Responsible for templatization & design of 150+ module Terraform service catalog, with the goal of "shift-left" of infrastructure-as-code to developers. These modules include actively-maintained READMEs, versioned releases, and backward compatibility for Terraform version & provider version updates.
- Addressed growing sprawl & cost of our manual certificate generation & rotation process by leveraging private & public Route 53 Hosted Zones and AWS Certificate Manager. Developers could then deploy a single Terraform module to secure & resolve their workloads from on-premises and, if necessary, from the public Internet.
- Modularized our multi-region AWS core networking architecture for edge web traffic inspection, load balancer sandwiching, and inter/intra-VPC networking (CloudWatch Logs, Direct Connect, Elastic IPs, Flow Logs, IAM, Network Interfaces, Route Tables, Security Groups, Transit Gateway, VPC, VPN Connections & Gateways)
- Built RSS-feed utility to notify our Teams Channel for updates to our Office 365 proxy allow list (DynamoDB, Lambda & SNS); custom Python library written for Symantic Bluecoat API to feed sed updates into our Secure Gateways.

Eaton Vance Management

Network Automation Engineer • Oct. 2017 — Apr, 2020

Focused on automating traditional enterprise networking infrastructure with Python scripting and Ansible playbooking.

- Designed network solutions and maintain service levels across 20 datacenters and remote offices.
- Introduced end-to-end workflow automation via Ansible and Python to infrastructure teams & management.
- Led liaising with engineers & business stakeholders to integrate acquisition networks.
- Drove efforts to standardize network infrastructure, and implement operations training for junior engineers.
- Participated on pilot team to implement Agile workflow and cross-team collaboration for infrastructure team.
- Worked with network visibility vendors to produce single pane-of-glass for identifying network pain points.

SS&C Technologies

Network Engineer • Oct. 2013 — Oct. 2017

Progressed from site-to-site VPN & firewall administration to design & deployment branch office and datacenter networks.

- Single point of contact for network troubleshooting and monitoring of 80+ global offices and datacenters.
- Built Solarwinds alerting & monitoring system to provide Helpdesk with necessary info for circuit outages.
- Built relationships and coordinated upgrades with local IT staff of our offices as large as 400+ users.
- Built relationships and coordinated upgrades with local IT staff of our offices as large as 400+ users.

Columbia University

Various Roles, Columbia University Information Technology (CUIT) • Sept. 2012 — May. 2014

- **Lab Consultant** responsible for support of lab patron needs.
- **UI Developer & Administrator** responsible for maintenance of Perl & Oracle DBM-based wiki for fellow consultants.

General Dynamics

Intern • May. 2013 — Aug. 2013

Responsible for supporting on-the-move (OTM) and at-the-halt (ATH) military ISP architecture.

Providence College

Various Roles, Providence College Information Technology (PCIT) & Ghana Sustainable Aid Project (GSAP) • Sept. 2010 — Aug. 2012

- **Computer Technician for PCIT** responsible for maintenance and deployment of faculty workstations.
- Community-Based Service Intern in Accra, Ghana responsible for developing a computer image in Ubuntu Linux for the Ghana Sustainable Aid Project (GSAP)'s Education Portal, for use in an internet cafe within Pokuase Village in Ga West, Ghana.

- **Research Assistant for GSAP** responsible for modeling a toilet prototype in Google Sketchup for use in developing nations.
- **Helpdesk Assistant for PCIT Helpdesk** the first line of defense for Providence College Information Technology.

Certification

Terraform Associate

Hashicorp • 2020

Cloud Solutions Architect - Associate

Amazon Web Services • 2019

Programming with Python

Codecademy • 2018

CCNA Routing & Switching

Cisco • 2015

CCENT

Cisco • 2015

Education

Columbia University

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering • 2012 - 2014

Providence College

Bachelor of Arts, Pre-Engineering • 2009 − 2012

Projects

The Jain-Taylor Family Cookbook

Developer • 2020 — Present

This is a personal project to maintain our family recipes in source control, using Jekyll & Github Pages to render the updated Markdown.

Resume

Developer • 2021 — Present

This is a personal project to keep my resume up to date, using a combination of Github Actions and Terraform Cloud to build the repository, and using Jekyll & Github Pages to render YAML.

Skills

Cloud Computing

I have been interested in cloud computing since 2014, starting by maintaining site-to-site VPNs to AWS. This has evolved to building small serverless microservices, as well as designing logging and modern web architectures. In my latest endeavor, I am driving design & maintenance of our organizations' account vending machine & landing zone.

Team Leadership & Management

My career has evolved from operating as an individual contributor to leading teams of operators, engineers, and architects as part of our Core Services. My ultimate goal is C-suite level management, in order to deliver large-scale organizational value through modern technology.

Open-Source & Closed-Source Development

I make strident efforts to design with open source in mind, whether through development of my own projects or contributions to existing projects. Where closed-source is required, I am avidly documenting specifics in our internal wiki, while providing usage instructions for developers to consume these projects effectively.

Infrastructure-as-Code

Through the use of Hashicorp Terraform and AWS CloudFormation, I have designed numerous playbooks and modules for many internal consumers, for resources varying from security groups, to common internal architecture patterns, to automated DNS & PKI infrastructure to ensure one-click security of our web services.

Networking Technologies

I have worked on various routing architectures, from traditional hub-based networking, to enterprise-grade routing and switching, to application-centric infrastructure, microsegmentation, and software-defined networking.

Associations

Hack.Diversity

Mentor • 2021

Hack Diversity is a talent provider of Black & Latinx technologists, supporting underrepresented talent with a yearly fellowship, incubator, and other programs. I am serving both as a mentor to one of the 2021 fellows, as well as providing educational opportunities related to cloud technologies.

Habitat for Humanity

Builds coordinator • 2013 − 2014

Developed new programs for our Habitat volunteers to participate in with the goal of learning more about the housing issues in New York City, and aim to discover local organizations with which to improve the Columbia community and to help our builds OCMs with their duties and responsibilities.

Inspired by <u>@iglovier</u>. Source project can be forked from <u>GitHub</u>.